<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Cryptocurrency Cafe</title><link href="http://bitcoin-class.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://bitcoin-class.org/feeds/announcements.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://bitcoin-class.org/</id><updated>2015-03-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Fall 2015 Course</title><link href="http://bitcoin-class.org/fall-2015-course.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-03-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>David Evans</name></author><id>tag:bitcoin-class.org,2015-03-26:fall-2015-course.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A similar course will be offered in Fall 2015.  It is listed as a cs4501
(Special Topics in Computer Science) with class meetings Mondays and
Wednesdays, 2-3:15pm in Olsson Hall 120.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://bitcoin-class.org/pages/syllabus.html"&gt;syllabus&lt;/a&gt; for this
semester's course will change some for the next version of the course,
but that page and the &lt;a href="http://bitcoin-class.org"&gt;rest of the material on this site&lt;/a&gt; will give you a
good idea what to expect.  The expected background for the Fall 2015
course is having completed cs2150 and cs3102 (or equivalent experience
and knowledge in some other way).  Exceptions will be made for students
who bring some other interesting background or perspective to the class.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Project Proposal Presentations</title><link href="http://bitcoin-class.org/project-proposal-presentations.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-03-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>David Evans</name></author><id>tag:bitcoin-class.org,2015-03-25:project-proposal-presentations.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Next week, each team will present their idea for the project.  You
should plan to have no more than 5-8 minutes to present your idea, and
then there will be some time for questions and discussion.  You can use
slides for your presentation (although it is fine is you want to present
without slides), but should have things set up on a laptop ready to go
when it is time for your team.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The schedule is below (but we won't rush the presentations Monday, so
some of the ones scheduled for Monday may be postponed to Wednesday).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Monday, 30 March&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Universal Coin Converter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Sam Abbate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Script Analysis in the Blockchain&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Saba Eskandarian&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;An Analysis and Breakdown of SHA Hashing in Bitcoin&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Jeremy Gabalski&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;An iOS Bitcoin Payment App&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
William Emmanuel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Examining Anonymous Marketplaces&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Max Serpe, Peter Gregrowski&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Financial Markets, Game Theory, and Self-Regulation&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Merlin Zhang, Trisha Hajela&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pointcoin Reddit Tip Bot&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Joey Weate, Charlie Harding&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Wednesday, 1 April&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;PointCoin Pizza &amp;mdash; Revamped&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Kyle Angelotti and Michelle Wang&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;PointList: the PointCoin Marketplace&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Anat Gilboa, Benjamin Edgar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kickstarting PointCoin&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Jake Shankman&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Studying Coinbase Reserves as a means of Predicting Market Price&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Alex Coffin, Ankit Gupta, Tara Raj, Corrigan Blanchfield&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Decentralized Banking Scheme for Communal Funds&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Ori Shimony&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bitcoin Market Price&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Oriana Ngo and Kevin Hoffman and Avinash Ramesh&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Subsidy Studies&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Laurence Meyers, Jacob Rosenberg&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Office Hours Snowed Out (now on Skype)</title><link href="http://bitcoin-class.org/office-hours-snowed-out-now-on-skype.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-03-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>David Evans</name></author><id>tag:bitcoin-class.org,2015-03-05:office-hours-snowed-out-now-on-skype.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I won't be able to hold my scheduled office hours today due to the
expected megastorm.  I will be available by skype (evans1629) during the
scheduled time (4-5pm) if anyone has project ideas to disucss or other
questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay warm and enjoy "Spring" break!&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Bitcoin Anthropology Talk</title><link href="http://bitcoin-class.org/bitcoin-anthropology-talk.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-02-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>David Evans</name></author><id>tag:bitcoin-class.org,2015-02-25:bitcoin-anthropology-talk.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The talk I mentioned in class today is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://llaannaa.com/"&gt;Lana Swartz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Annenberg School for
Communication and Journalism, USC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Title: &lt;em&gt;Social Transactions: The Meaning and Management of New Payment Infrastructures&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When: &lt;strong&gt;Thursday, February 26, 2015, 3:30-4:30 pm&lt;/strong&gt; (note this overlaps with my scheduled office hours; I'll still have my office hours on Thursday and won't be able to make it to the talk, but I hope some of you will be able to make it to this and summarize it for us)  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where: &lt;strong&gt;New Cabell Hall 299a&lt;/strong&gt;
Host: Media Studies Department&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ABSTRACT: Money is an interface between people, and it connects them to
larger imaginaries like the "nation" and the "economy." Monetary
transactions depend on infrastructures, which are always instantiations
of relations and meaning. In recent years, economic downturn paired with
high penetration of information and communication technology has led to
an explosion of imagination and innovation around the form of
money. Many have begun to rethink the very infrastructures through which
value is measured and transferred. In particular, the tech industry has
discovered payment. What was once a slow-moving and marginalized sector
of consumer financial services is being rethought as a form of social
media. This talk considers how the infrastructures of payment are being
taken apart and put back together in new configurations by Silicon
Valley. Models native to social media are coming into contact with long
standing practices in the payments industry. What are the implications
of this interaction for the broader social functions of money and its
infrastructures? It is important now to understand this democratization
and, crucially, privatization of transaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Biography:&lt;/strong&gt; Lana Swartz is a PhD candidate at the Annenberg School for
Communication and Journalism at the University of Southern
California. Previously, she received an SM in Comparative Media Studies
from the Massachusetts Institute of Technology. Most of her research is
about money and other networked communication technologies. She was
published payment technologies such as a Diners' Club, the first third
party charge card, and Bitcoin, the anarcho-capitalist cryptographic
currency.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>PointCoin Updates</title><link href="http://bitcoin-class.org/pointcoin-updates.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-02-23T21:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>David Evans</name></author><id>tag:bitcoin-class.org,2015-02-23:pointcoin-updates.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reminder:&lt;/strong&gt; We'll have a quiz in class Wednesday.  It will be similar
  to the previous quiz, and focus on fundamental understanding on how
  bitcoin works covering material from the beginning of the class
  through &lt;a href="http://bitcoin-class.org/class-10-more-mining.html"&gt;Class 10&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mining:&lt;/strong&gt;
You'll notice in the PointCoin blockchain that I'm now running an
"unfair advantage" node, using a Medium instance on EC2.  This is at the
insistance of the PointCoin Pizza purveyor, who is worried that it may
be too easy for a single miner to obtain a high fraction of the
processing power just by managing their EC2 micro instance credits
carefully while everyone else's miner is throttled.  (You can see this
in the blockchain when a new miner starts up, it will often win several
blocks in a row, just because it has not yet hit the micro instance
throttling level.)  (I may decide to turn off my "unfair advantage"
miner at some later time, but for now I intend to leave it running to
make it a difficult for a single miner to obtain control of a large
fraction of the hashing power.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Talk Tuesday!&lt;/strong&gt;: There's an interesting security-related talk from &lt;a href="https://ericw.us/trow/"&gt;Eric
Wustrow&lt;/a&gt; tomorrow: &lt;a href="http://www.cs.virginia.edu/events/colloquia/wustrow.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Anticensorship in the
Network&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;,
10:45am in Rice 242.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>PointCoin Pizza</title><link href="http://bitcoin-class.org/pointcoin-pizza.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-02-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>David Evans</name></author><id>tag:bitcoin-class.org,2015-02-21:pointcoin-pizza.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The PointCoin currency has now reached the level of stability and market
acceptance, that merchants are beginning to accept it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://pizza.bitcoin-class.com/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PointCoin Pizza&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is now open and
accepting orders.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that PointCoin Pizza's opening hours are unpredicatable and
unannounced, so there is no guarantee that your pizza order will be
delivered within a reasonable time.  The price of pizza is currently 150
PTC, but it may go up rapidly depending on market conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spend your PointCoins carefully, though.  You don't want to be reading about
&lt;a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/ericmack/2013/12/23/the-bitcoin-pizza-purchase-thats-worth-7-million-today/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Bitcoin Pizza Purchase That's Worth $7 Million Today&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Project 2 - New Network Up</title><link href="http://bitcoin-class.org/project-2-new-network-up.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-02-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>David Evans</name></author><id>tag:bitcoin-class.org,2015-02-17:project-2-new-network-up.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The new PointCoin network is now up!  This fixes the reset problem and
some other issues that were discussed in Monday's class.  It also sets
the expected block generating time to 10 minutes and the mining reward
to 10 PointCoin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To migrate your node to the PointCoin 0.2 network follow these directions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/PointCoin/pointcoind/wiki/Migration"&gt;Migration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you have your node running on the new network, add your public IP address here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/PointCoin/pointcoind/wiki/Publicly-Listed-IP-Address"&gt;Node Addresses&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no automatic peering.  We believe this is a design decision in
btcd (which pointcoind is forked from), to not trust any node that is
not announced by multiple other nodes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see the blockchain at:
&lt;a href="http://blockexplorer.bitcoin-class.org/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://blockexplorer.bitcoin-class.org/&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.
We will consider this the canonical PointCoin blockchain (at least until
next Monday, when you can start launching attacks).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of the problems with the network, it is no longer necessary to
acquire 100 PointCoin to earn full credit for Problem 1.  It is
sufficient to successfully mine at least one block.  Earning more
PointCoin will still be beneficial though!  You'll have other
opportunities to use it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks a bunch to Alex and Nick for tremendous work getting this
working!  It seems to be stable, and our nodes (including nodes running
on EC2 micro instances) have been stable (no crashes) for more than 24
hours now, so we're optimistic there will not be further problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm really sorry for the confusion and trouble this has caused, not to
mention the PointCoins you've lost that you may have mined successfully
on the original network.  I think we'll learn a lot from trying to
launch a cryptocurrency, and there is plenty that can go wrong.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Project 2</title><link href="http://bitcoin-class.org/project-2.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-02-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>David Evans</name></author><id>tag:bitcoin-class.org,2015-02-11:project-2.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://bitcoin-class.org/pages/project2.html"&gt;Project 2&lt;/a&gt; is now
posted.  The first part is due &lt;strong&gt;February 22&lt;/strong&gt;.  (After February 23, we
will be encouraging you to try launching attacks on the PointCoin
network, which is Part 2 of this project.  Until then, though, you
should aim to be a cooperative and honest pointcoin node and miner.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you haven't already got your pointcoin node up and running on an EC2
node, you should definitely get this done by the end of this week.
(Note: Dave has office hours Thursday 4-5pm, and Nick/Alex has office
hours Friday noon-2pm.  Please don't wait to get help if you are stuck
on this!)&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Starting Project 2</title><link href="http://bitcoin-class.org/starting-project-2.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-02-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>David Evans</name></author><id>tag:bitcoin-class.org,2015-02-05:starting-project-2.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project 1.&lt;/strong&gt; You should have received your Project 1 grade as a
  transfer to your vanity address (on a 100,000 satoshi scale, so 0.001
  BTC is full credit).  You should be able to see this in the blockchain
  (e.g., by searching for your vanity address).  Note that this is
  different from the address you used to create your initial wallet, so
  you won't see it in your wallet unless you load the keys for your
  vanity address into your wallet (see
  &lt;a href="https://multibit.org/en/help/v0.5/help_importingPrivateKeys.html"&gt;https://multibit.org/en/help/v0.5/help_importingPrivateKeys.html&lt;/a&gt;
  for how to import your vanity address private key into MultiBit).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geting started on Project 2.&lt;/strong&gt; For project 2, you'll be implementing
  and running a miner for a new cryptocurrency,
  &lt;a href="https://github.com/PointCoin/pointcoind"&gt;PointCoin&lt;/a&gt;.  We'll talk more
  about this in class Monday and post a more detailed project
  descruption soon, but you should get started by setting up your
  pointcoind node before class Monday.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Directions for getting your
  pointcoind node setup on a free EC2 instance are here: &lt;a href="https://github.com/PointCoin/pointcoind/wiki/Installing-PointCoin-on-AWS"&gt;Installing
  PointCoin on
  AWS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you get stuck, we'll have time in class Monday to help, but you
  should get as far as you can on your own before class Monday.  Feel
  free to also post coments and questions here.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Extra Office Hours</title><link href="http://bitcoin-class.org/extra-office-hours.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-01-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>David Evans</name></author><id>tag:bitcoin-class.org,2015-01-29:extra-office-hours.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alex Kuck&lt;/strong&gt; has offered to hold some extra office hours this evening
  to help out on Project 1.  You'll find him in the Rice Hall common
  area (the space next to the bagel shop) today, 5-7pm.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Office Hours</title><link href="http://bitcoin-class.org/office-hours.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-01-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>David Evans</name></author><id>tag:bitcoin-class.org,2015-01-24:office-hours.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here's the office hours schedule, starting this week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;David Evans&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
Mondays right after class.&lt;br /&gt;
Thursdays, 4-5pm in Rice 507.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nick Skelsey&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
Monday nights from 5-7pm in Rice 442 (Dave's lab).&lt;br /&gt;
Fridays from 12-2pm at &lt;a href="http://hackcville.com"&gt;Hackcville&lt;/a&gt; (#9 Elliewood Ave).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that you can see these, as well as other events in the class in the
&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/calendar/embed?src=rmjagdrnmu3a9h2q5199lg4t28%40group.calendar.google.com&amp;amp;ctz=America/New_York"&gt;course
calendar&lt;/a&gt;
(which you should be able to embed in your own calendar).  When we need
to canel or reschedule office hours, it will be updated on the course
calendar.  &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Communication in Cryptocurrency Cafe</title><link href="http://bitcoin-class.org/communication-in-cryptocurrency-cafe.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-01-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>David Evans</name></author><id>tag:bitcoin-class.org,2015-01-23:communication-in-cryptocurrency-cafe.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here's some information on how communication will be done for this course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I prefer to avoid using email for group communication, so won't be email
spamming the entire class except when it really seems necessary.
Instead, nearly all (electronic) communication will be done through the
course website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can subscribe to the site using an RSS reader, or receive an email
notification everytime the site is updated by using a service like
&lt;a href="https://blogtrottr.com/"&gt;https://blogtrottr.com/&lt;/a&gt; and subscribing to
&lt;code&gt;bitcoin-class.org&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of the pages on the course site will include a disqus discussion
forum.  If you don't already have an account with disqus, you can create
one the first time you post a comment (or sign-on to disqus using a
Google, Facebook, or Twitter account, if you don't mind you disqus
activities being visible to another provider).  You can also post
anonymously and should use this when you feel it is necessary, but
otherwise, please post using a name that will be recognizable to me and
your classmates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't want to force pseudo-discussion by making it a course
requirement to make a certain number of contributions to the on-line
discussions, but do encourage everyone to use the fora to contribute to
both your own learning and building the course community, and to provide
value to others in the class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the page-specific disqus comments, you can use the
&lt;a href="http://bitcoin-class.org/pages/forum.html"&gt;general forum&lt;/a&gt; for discussions that don't
fit into particular topics.  Feel free to use that forum to post links
and thoughts about any related information you find, as well as general
comments broadly relevant to the course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can control settings in disqus to determine when you receive email
notifications (including subscribing to notifications for any comments
on the course site if you want, or getting a daily or weekly digest).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have a non-confidential question about a course assignment or
content, please use the web site forums to ask it instead of emailing me
directly.  This way, I (or others) can respond in a way that will be
visible to everyone else who might have the same question.  Feel free to
use email to contact me directly for questions that are private or not
relevant to the rest of the class.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Key Chase</title><link href="http://bitcoin-class.org/key-chase.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-01-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>David Evans</name></author><id>tag:bitcoin-class.org,2015-01-22:key-chase.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As mentioned in class today, each of you should have received a small
deposit in your wallet.  You will need this for Project 1, but should
also use it as a starting point for attempting to learn as much as you
can about how we transfered funds (and possibly solve the puzzle leading
to something interesting).  You can try tracing the transaction both
forward and backward, trying to learn things like: where did the initial
coin come from and when did I buy it, how long did it take for all the
coin to be distributed, how much did it cost in transaction fees, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that each of you had a different bitcoin address, so you all have
different starting points for examining the transactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Post interesting things you find about this in the discussion below.
(Note: the discussion won't appear on the main index page.  Click on the
title link to enter the article page that will include the discussion.)&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry></feed>