<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Cryptocurrency Cafe</title><link href="http://bitcoin-class.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://bitcoin-class.org/feeds/announcements.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://bitcoin-class.org/</id><updated>2014-01-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Office Hours</title><link href="http://bitcoin-class.org/office-hours.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-01-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>David Evans</name></author><id>tag:bitcoin-class.org,2014-01-24:office-hours.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here's the office hours schedule, starting this week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;David Evans&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
Mondays right ater class.&lt;br /&gt;
Thursdays, 4-5pm in Rice 507.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nick Skelsey&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
Monday nights from 5-7pm in Rice 442 (Dave's lab).
Fridays from 12-2pm at &lt;a href="http://hackcville.com"&gt;Hackcville&lt;/a&gt; (#9 Elliewood Ave).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that you can see these, as well as other events in the class in the
&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/calendar/embed?src=rmjagdrnmu3a9h2q5199lg4t28%40group.calendar.google.com&amp;amp;ctz=America/New_York"&gt;course
calendar&lt;/a&gt;
(which you should be able to embed in your own calendar).  When we need
to canel or reschedule office hours, it will be updated on the course
calendar.  &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Communication in Cryptocurrency Cafe</title><link href="http://bitcoin-class.org/communication-in-cryptocurrency-cafe.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-01-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>David Evans</name></author><id>tag:bitcoin-class.org,2014-01-23:communication-in-cryptocurrency-cafe.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here's some information on how communication will be done for this course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I prefer to avoid using email for group communication, so won't be email
spamming the entire class except when it really seems necessary.
Instead, nearly all (electronic) communication will be done through the
course website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can subscribe to the site using an RSS reader, or receive an email
notification everytime the site is updated by using a service like
&lt;a href="https://blogtrottr.com/"&gt;https://blogtrottr.com/&lt;/a&gt; and subscribing to
&lt;code&gt;bitcoin-class.org&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of the pages on the course site will include a disqus discussion
forum.  If you don't already have an account with disqus, you can create
one the first time you post a comment (or sign-on to disqus using a
Google, Facebook, or Twitter account, if you don't mind you disqus
activities being visible to another provider).  You can also post
anonymously and should use this when you feel it is necessary, but
otherwise, please post using a name that will be recognizable to me and
your classmates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't want to force pseudo-discussion by making it a course
requirement to make a certain number of contributions to the on-line
discussions, but do encourage everyone to use the fora to contribute to
both your own learning and building the course community, and to provide
value to others in the class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the page-specific disqus comments, you can use the
&lt;a href="http://bitcoin-class.org/pages/forum.html"&gt;general forum&lt;/a&gt; for discussions that don't
fit into particular topics.  Feel free to use that forum to post links
and thoughts about any related information you find, as well as general
comments broadly relevant to the course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can control settings in disqus to determine when you receive email
notifications (including subscribing to notifications for any comments
on the course site if you want, or getting a daily or weekly digest).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have a non-confidential question about a course assignment or
content, please use the web site forums to ask it instead of emailing me
directly.  This way, I (or others) can respond in a way that will be
visible to everyone else who might have the same question.  Feel free to
use email to contact me directly for questions that are private or not
relevant to the rest of the class.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Key Chase</title><link href="http://bitcoin-class.org/key-chase.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-01-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>David Evans</name></author><id>tag:bitcoin-class.org,2014-01-22:key-chase.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As mentioned in class today, each of you should have received a small
deposit in your wallet.  You will need this for Project 1, but should
also use it as a starting point for attempting to learn as much as you
can about how we transfered funds (and possibly solve the puzzle leading
to something interesting).  You can try tracing the transaction both
forward and backward, trying to learn things like: where did the initial
coin come from and when did I buy it, how long did it take for all the
coin to be distributed, how much did it cost in transaction fees, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that each of you had a different bitcoin address, so you all have
different starting points for examining the transactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Post interesting things you find about this in the discussion below.
(Note: the discussion won't appear on the main index page.  Click on the
title link to enter the article page that will include the discussion.)&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry></feed>